Mahdi Karimi

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

I am a competent engineer with rich hands-on experience in Software engineering. My greatest strength is my commitment to learning and finding better solutions to overcome challenges. I aimed to further my experience in software craftsmanship and architecture design.

EXPERIENCE

Alibaba Travels Co. (APRIL 2021 - PRESENT)

- Alibaba academy mentorship
- Developed a versatile golang framework helping the company quickly integrate 10+ hotel data providers saving large amount of resources and time
- Refactored large scale hotel central reservation system (CRS) within 4 months from vue 2 and webpack to vue 3, typescript and vite
- Maintained and refactored Nuxt Back office panels using vue 2
- Refactored Alibaba.ir/hotel views with typescript and vue3
- Contributed on professional career path of company/'s frontend engineers
- · Contributed on company/'s OSS projects such as Vuilerplate
- Developed visualization tools to improve DX and onboarding processes
- Contribution and maintenance of alibaba.ir/hotel frontend website using Vue 3 and typescript

Snapp! Market (FEBRUARY 2021 - OCTOBER 2022)

- Practiced requirements engineering and research and development on multiple IoT projects
- Developed esp8266 hardware firmware using C++ and Arduino libraries
- Developed required infrastructure i.e. server and client panels for needed IoT management systems
- Worked directly with other engineers building production-ready PCBs and physical products very rapidly

Freelance (2018 - APRIL 2021)

- Created and maintained multiple wordpress projects
- Advised multiple clients on single page applications and their bushiness websites
- Developed telegram bots helping bushiness reach more customers faster and easier
- Developed numerous e-commerce projects for multiple clients
- Developed a dynamic restaurant digital signage system

PROJECTS

Open Source Projects

I spent my freetimes developing fun and practical projects that can teach me new things about new subjects

- VSCode webvue extension
- Wireguard Insights

Radio Upstream Podcast

Description...

PUBLICATIONS

Technical Blog Posts

I write technical and non technical blogs posts and share them with the world on medium

EDUCATION

BNUT - Babol Noshirvani University of Technology (2019 - PRESENT) Bachelor of Science

SKILLS

Semantic HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ECMAScript 6+)
TailwindCSS, BulmaCSS and BootstrapCSS
TypeScript
Vue2, Vue3 and Nuxt
React.js, Next.js
Software Engineering
Continuous Integration, Continuous Development
Docker, Kubernetes
Agile
Golang

INTERESTS

Creating beautiful, responsive, fast and accessible UIs Reading technical books and writing my thoughts Building computers Embedded programming, arduinos and raspberry pies Renewable energy, Solar panels and automated houses

CONTACT

Tehran, Iran mhdi_kr@outlook.com